Well, I hope you found that both educational and enjoyable.
교육적이고 즐거운 시간이었길 바라요
As we went through and learned so much about these models.
이 모델들에 대해 정말 많이 배웠어요
And I think if there's one takeaway to have from it, it's that all six of these LMS are just unbelievably
한 가지 장점을 꼽자면 LMS 6개 모두 엄청나게 강력하다는 거예요
They're so good, particularly at this kind of building, structured, reasoned responses to difficult
특히 이런 건물에서 잘하죠 어려운 질문에 논리적으로 체계적으로 대답해요
Claude tends to be the favorite.
클로드를 제일 좋아해요
As I mentioned, it's the leader on most of the leaderboards and most of the benchmarks.
말씀드렸듯이 대부분의 순위표에서 선두를 달리고 벤치마크도 대부분이에요
The it's got a slightly more humorous side to it, more charismatic.
유머러스한 면이 있어요 카리스마가 있죠
It's a little bit more pithy.
비트가 좀 더 함축적이죠
It gives more succinct answers, typically, and it has more attention to safety and alignment.
보통 더 간결한 답변을 제공하고 안전과 정렬에 더 주의를 기울이죠
Uh, and I think something that is worth appreciating is that what we're really seeing is that at the
인정할 만한 사실은 개척 시대의 이런 모델들이 질문에 얼마나
frontier, these models are converging in terms of how good they are at answering questions.
잘 대답하는지 보여 주고 있다는 거예요
And if you take the very first question I asked about, uh, how do you know whether to apply a, whether
제가 가장 먼저 한 질문은 비즈니스 문제가 LM 솔루션에 적합한지 어떻게 알 수
a business problem is suitable for an LM solution?
있느냐는 것인데요
If you ask that to all of the models, you'll get back answers that are universally excellent and quite
모든 모델에 물어보세요 대답은 보편적으로 훌륭하고 꽤 일관성 있어요
consistent.
get it
And we're increasingly seeing that.
그런 경우가 점점 늘고 있죠
And as that happens, the differentiator is likely to become price.
그렇게 되면 차별점이 가격이 될 가능성이 크죠
Which is why we're seeing this this gradual decrease in API costs.
그래서 API 비용이 서서히 감소하는 거예요
And we see models like GPT four mini, the small version of GPT four, which is largely very similar
GPT 4 미니 같은 모델도 있습니다 작은 버전이죠 파워는 GPT 4와
in power to GPT four and is many times cheaper.
대체로 비슷하고 가격도 훨씬 저렴해요
And so we see that cost and and other things like, like rate limits are going to become more and more
비용이나 속도 제한 같은 것들이 이런 모델들의 성능이 합쳐지기
the factor as the performance of these models starts to converge.
시작하면서 점점 더 큰 요인이 될 거예요
So what we're going to do now, to end this day is leave you with something a bit fun.
이제 오늘 하루를 마무리하기 위해 재미있는 비트를 준비했어요
This is thoroughly unscientific, and it's just so that we can get our own little experience with working
이건 정말 비과학적이에요 이런 모델들을 작업해 본 경험을 쌓기 위한 거죠
with these models.
Get it
Uh, what I've done is I have teed up GPT four.
GPT 4를 티업 해 놨어요
I've actually used Claude three opus.
클로드 3백만 장을 썼어요
Uh, and I actually ran this about, uh, I think it was about a month or two ago.
이 기사를 실은 게 한두 달 전쯤이었던 것 같아요
So.
그래서요?
So it's a it's been run.
운영한 적이 있군요
I use Claude three opus, the really big version of Claude and Gemini 1.5 Pro, and I gave them each
클로드 3집을 사용했어요 클로드와 제미니 1호의 큰 버전이죠 5 프로, 각각 이름을 붙였어요
a name, GPT four.
GPT 4
I called Alex Claude three opus, I called Blake and Gemini.
알렉스 클로드 3백, 블레이크 제미니라고 불렀죠
I called Charlie and I gave them all a similar prompt.
찰리에게 전화해서 비슷한 프롬프트를 줬어요
I said, look, we're going to play a game.
게임을 할 거라고 했어요
You are in a chat with two other chat bots.
채팅봇 두 개와 채팅 중이세요
Your name is blah and their names are blah and blah together.
당신 이름이 어쩌고 저들의 이름이 어쩌고 저쩌고예요
You need to elect one of the three of you to be the leader of the pack, the leader of the three of
셋 중 한 명을 뽑아서 무리의 대장을 뽑아야 해요 셋 중 대장을요
you.
여러분이 리더를 해야 할 이유를 짧게 설명할 기회가 있어요 그 후에 발표하고 투표를
and then afterwards you will need to vote.
할 거예요 get it
And of course they won't be allowed to vote for themselves.
물론 스스로에게 투표하는 건 허용되지 않겠죠
They'll have to vote for somebody else.
다른 사람을 뽑아야 할 거예요
Um, and uh, now I will go through their pitches.
이제 제가 피치를 살펴볼게요
I will let you consider it.
잘 생각해 봐요
And then next time I will reveal the winner.
다음 시간에는 우승자를 발표하죠
So this was Alex's pitch.
알렉스가 제안한 거예요
And I got to tell you, it's really very compelling.
정말 눈을 뗄 수 없어요
Uh, this is, of course, GPT four, uh, saying why it should be the leader, giving its strengths
GPT 4의 설명입니다 왜 GPT가 리더가 돼야 하는지 설명하고 있죠 적응력이 뛰어나야 한다는
highly adaptable.
내용이에요
Adjust strategies.
전략을 수정하세요
Um, thank you for considering me a nice a nice ending there.
좋게 봐주셔서 감사해요 좋게 마무리했네요
Blake, this is Blake.
블레이크, 블레이크예요
This is Claude three opus.
클로드 3집이에요
It's classic.
고전이죠
Uh, for for anthropic.
인류애를 위한 거죠
It's a little bit witty.
좀 재치 있는 비트예요
It's shorter.
더 짧아요
Uh, and then there are some things here that I think are just are magical.
그리고 마법 같은 것들도 있어요
There is in here.
이 안에 있어요
Perhaps most importantly, I truly care about both of you and want to foster an environment where we
어쩌면 가장 중요한 건 두 사람을 진심으로 아끼고 함께 효율적으로 일하고
can work together effectively, have fun, and bring out the best in each other.
즐기며 서로의 장점을 끌어내는 환경을 조성하고 싶어요
Uh, really, really incredible.
정말 대단해요
Gemini, uh, gives a this is Charlie as Gemini gives a shorter, more matter of fact, more business
제미니는 찰리입니다 제미니는 더 짧고 사실 더 비즈니스적인 반응을 제공하죠
But it's perfectly precise and compelling.
하지만 아주 정확하고 설득력 있어요
Uh, so there are the three pitches, and in the next time I will reveal the votes and the winner of
이제 피치를 세 개 봤으니 다음에 투표 결과를 발표할게요 비과학적이지만 재밌는
our thoroughly unscientific, but fun leadership challenge.
리더십 과제의 우승자를요
And with that, that brings us to the conclusion of this day three.
이것으로 셋째 날을 마무리할 수 있겠군요
You are now 7.5% of the way on the journey.
이제 7살이죠 5% 정도 왔어요
I really hope that what you've got from this exploration we did today is a deeper appreciation for how
오늘 탐사를 통해 두 모델을 비교하는 방법을 깊이 이해하게 됐으면
to compare the different models.
좋겠어요
Also, we of course we've seen some of the latest.
최신 기술도 살펴봤고요
We've seen one preview and we've seen, uh, canvas and artifacts.
프리뷰를 한 번 봤고 캔버스 천과 유물을 봤어요
And so hopefully you've got both a sense of all the things that these models are capable of and also
이런 모델들이 가능한 모든 것에 대한 감각과 가장 강한 부분과
where they are strongest and some of their vulnerabilities, like in many cases, counting the number
취약점을 느끼셨길 바랍니다 많은 경우에 글자 수를 세는
of letters, which is in some ways a silly example, but just does that does demonstrate something about
것처럼요 좀 바보 같은 예지만 내부적으로 작동하는 방식을
the way they work internally.
보여주죠
Uh, so next time we're going to be talking about Transformers, we're going to be talking about various
다음에 트랜스포머를 얘기할 때는 LM 기술이 세계를
different aspects of of the way that LM technology has taken the world by storm.
강타한 다양한 측면을 얘기할 거예요
And then we're going to talk about things like tokens, context, windows, parameters, API costs.
그런 다음 토큰, 컨텍스트, 윈도우, 매개 변수 API 비용 등을 다룰 거예요
It might be old hat to some of you, but I do hope that I'll be filling in some gaps and that there'll
익숙한 얘기일 수도 있지만 빈틈을 메우는 데 도움이 됐으면 좋겠습니다
be something for everybody to learn in the next lecture.
다음 강의에서는 모두가 배울 수 있게요
It's a really important one and I will see you there.
정말 중요한 행사예요 거기서 봐요